ALEX TRAUTMAN

www.alextrautman.me

STATEMENT

I am an organized, thoughtful and compassionate frontend developer with strong communication skills, a high attention to detail and a penchant for learning new technologies. I have professional experience teaching math and working with teenagers in the mental health industry.

CONTACT

433 Euclid Terrace NE #3, Atlanta GA 30307

T: (617) 930-2539

E: alexitrautman@gmail.com

L: linkedin.com/in/alextrautman

EDUCATION

BA. COMPUTER SCIENCE 2011 - 2015

Carleton College - Northfield, MN

MATH EDUCATION RESIDENCY 2016

High Mountain Institue - Leadville, CO

SKILLS

LANGUAGES LIBRARIES TOOLS

Adobe Photoshop **JavaScript** React.js HTML₅ Adobe Illustrator jQuery **CSS** Bootstrap Sketch / InVision

MySQL Greensock GSAP

Bash Wordpress D₃.is

EXPERIENCE

2018 THE NEW SCHOOL OF ATLANTA

Backend Bootcamp Head Instructor

Designed and developed curriculum guiding high school juniors in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Assisted students create websites for local businesses in culminating hackathon.

VILLAGE - GOODIE NATION PREACCELERATOR PROGRAM 2017 - 2018

Founder

Created concept for an app to develop emotional intelligence in young boys. Independently constructed beautiful mockups in Sketch and InVision. Won Best Chatbot App Design award at Hack the Violence hackathon.

FOURCUBED 2015 - 2016

Frontend Developer

Learned full stack development in Node is, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, rising from part-time intern to salaried employee. Designed layouts for new website launch, built frontend, communicated with API.

RECENT PROJECTS

React.is · **BICYCLE GEOMETRY · STAT KEEPER**

JavaScript · HTML

·CSS

Developing tool to visualize bicycle geometry given a set of manufacturers' measurements. Project also included trigonometry, JavaScript's math library and Paper.js. Project coming to my website soon.

D3.js · ReGL ·

DATA VISUALIZATIONS

HTML · CSS

Independent projects exploring astronaut flight time using data from NASA and incidents of gun violence in Georgia with help from the Gun Violence Archive.

James Watson

Head of School at New School of Atlanta E: james@tnsatlanta.org

Chap Capra

Chief Technology Officer at FourCubed E: chad.capra@gmail.com

Carrie Mallozzi

Head of School at High Mountain Institude E: cmallozzi@hminet.org